Greetings from Jerusalem, Israel!
Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday service
The purpose and the reason why I paid such a visit to the mayor of Jerusalem was
for the important pilgrimage for the viewers and lovers of Emmanuel TV all over the world.
I want that kind of pilgrimage so you can visit places you have read so much about in the bible.
This is why I visited the mayor of Jerusalem.
and other officials of Parliament and other;
to let them know that my people are
coming from all over the world,
to pay a visit to the most important places you have read so much about.
And there are many places there that some of the pilgrimages may not have the grace to visit.
When I was there there are some places they took me to. People don't go there because of security.
Like Abraham and Sarah sites and many other places like that.
You will not see any pilgrimage there. While millions of pilgrimages are going everywhere.
I want those places for you. I want them to add that one when you are going.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So, this is very important. And also make an arrangement with a tour guide to take you all over Israel.
Also schedule a meeting with the authority.
So you will be recognized as a priesthood.
Not just a pilgrimage, but someone they should honor and respect when you visit them.
I love you so much. This is why I paid such a visit to Jerusalem's mayor.
I know many of you have visited many places in Israel.
There are many places you have actually never visited.
You have visited Israel many times, but there are some places you would be willing to visit.
So, I think that this time is an opportunity.
When it is time I will let you know. And it will be a quota system for each country,
Emmanuel TV viewers are all over the world.
They want to visit.
Once they are there for six days, on the seventh day I can flight there to meet and pray with them.
so that by then you would have visited everywhere.
I will be there just one or two days.
Pray with you in any location the Spirit of God directs.
Then congratulate you and come back home.
Hallelujah!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Try to meet some tour guide that will be taking people around.
So during the testimonies the Spirit of God reminded me and said:
"talk to your people about LET LOVE LEAD." So that they will know so much about it.
We have been talking about this issue of love
because faith cannot work without love.
Let's just quickly look at a force called love.
Let me take you to the Book of 1 John
1 John chapter 4
God's love and ours.
Take note of the title there.
Verse 7.
1 John chapter 4 verse 7
The title is "God's love and ours".
This means there are two kinds of love: God's love and ours.
Ok. I'll read verse 7.
"Dear Friends, let us love one another, for love comes from God."
Everyone who loves has been born of God and knows God.
Whoever does not love does not know God, because God is love.
Hallelujah!
This is how God showed his love among his people.
He sent his one and only son to the world that we might live through him.
Let's go to the Book of 1 Corinthians
Chapter 13 verse 13.
1 Corinthians Chapter 13 verse 13.
"And now these three remain: faith, hope and love. But the greatest of these is love."
So we say LET LOVE LEAD.
What does that mean in that 1 Corinthians Chapter 13 verse 13?
It says love is the greatest.
If love is the greatest, what else again?
If love is the greatest, this means that without love, nothing can work. You cannot work without love.
Your attitude cannot work.
If you are kind, very good, or just mention any attribute you claim you have.
Without love that cannot work.
It means if you laugh without love, you are laughing, not God.
But you can laugh and God laughs.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When we laugh in love and faith, God laughs.
When you pray in love and faith, God prays.
So you say you are the one praying; no it's God
When you preach in love and faith, God preaches.
So, in that 1 John 4:7
It says, "beloved, let us love for love is God and God is love."
Everyone who loves is born of God for love is God and God is love.
Can you see the position of God when I say LET LOVE LEAD?
You say, how can love lead? Yes it can.
If you fail to walk in love, you almost shut down your spiritual walk with the Lord.
Failure to walk in love can almost shut down our spiritual walk with the Lord.
It can shut down your relationship with God. Failure to walk in love.
When I say LET LOVE LEAD, you should understand what I am talking about.
Love is the force that sets everything working.
Your kindness, goodness, humility, faith or just mention any quality you can talk about.
Love is the force that sets them working.
Without love, your kindness, goodness, faithfulness and obedience will be dormant.
When you say, [laugh] without love,
you are laughing of yourself.
[laugh] with love, you are laughing with God.
Love looks around to see who is in need. Tell your neighbor [...].
Love looks around to see who is in need.
Love looks around to see who is unsaved.
You have love.
The love of God.
Love looks around. As you are sitting, you look around you.
Who is sick? What can you do to help?
What assistance can you give?
You begin to think about that because you are born of love.
You begin to think about this man sitting behind me,
the way I am looking at him is not comfortable.
You may because of the man move toward the usher.
And say usher, can I see you please?
There is a man behind me. It looks like it will need help and I don't know how to go about it.
Would you please approach (talk to) him?
When you look around you, you will see those who are in need of what you have.
Maybe he does not have anything, no money to buy food.
He even had to borrow money to come here.
You can now on your own, "excuse me". "How are you?", "fine".
Would you mind to see me? "Yes." He would not mind to see you.
But for your own love, one must meet you and say "Uncle I need your help".
That is your (way of expressing) love.
"Uncle I need your help." I have not eaten today.
"Please help me." You will now bring money out. That is your own (way of expressing) love.
Which is not God's love.
This is why the title here says, "God's love and ours"
Your own (way of expressing) love: if they do not ask you, you will not give.
If they person is not falling [sound of need], you will not help.
You always help for selfish, classic, and material reasons. For reasons known to you you help.
Love looks around to see who is in need, crying, lamenting. People you can see.
If you have that love, God will give you his face and his eyes to see them.
No matter how little or how poor you are,
There are many people that are still in need of what you have;
People you are better than.
When you say you don't have anything, OK. There could be something that is better than anything.
Something can be better than anything, but your language is always; "I don't have anything."
Take this word:
The world needs to see our unity and our love for one another.
If we have God's love, tell your neighbor; the world needs to see our unity and our love for one another.
Yes, if you have God's love; the world will see our unity and our love for one another.
But we fight ourselves. If you know you cannot join bare fighting you just remain quiet.
This is why I remain quiet because you will not be able to quote me.
If I want to be your friend and I know you are not ready to be my friend, you remain quiet.
I am not isolated but I decided to be quiet because which direction will I follow?
Yes, that does not stop me; that is my nature.
I will not live by history, I will live according to God's what?
God's direction.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I will live according to God's direction.
Just like the last time I traveled when I traveled to Israel,
I said OK, I must pay a visit to Bethlehem.
When I entered Bethlehem, I said "no" I will not enter Bethlehem without seeing the mayor of Bethlehem.
It is not possible for me.
If I am not going to see the mayor of Bethlehem, I will not go to Bethlehem.
People were saying, "mayor of Bethlehem?"
Who is this man? Then, I introduced myself. I am T.B. Joshua.
Before I know it they quickly searched the Internet, "250 million follow this man all over the world".
Anywhere/whoever you want to visit, we are ready to take you there. They are not like us here.
They respect people integrity and reputation.
You know, the Internet is a global thing. If you say you are somebody, they will type your name; simple!
They give a call, "so and so person", "what is name?" T.B. Joshua?
Just T.B. Joshua without going to the Internet,
the mayor said, "please, I am going to leave everything I am doing I want to see the man."
"Please let him come." As I came he said, "how are you?" I said, "fine."
We discussed... "I am here in your city Bethlehem."
Since you are the governor and everything here,
before I enter the city I said, "let me say hello to you."
He entertained me and gave me an award and we discussed...
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So from there they appointed a tour guide.
Sir, where or anywhere you want to go this tour guide will take you around.
I said, "OK, but I still want to come back and see you mayor." he said, "OK".
Moving around, they took me to one hospital we passed to the place we were going to see;
and I saw sick people everywhere.
People were saying [sick sound]
You know I am not used to see people in pain.
Even when I am praying for people here, and I see people in pain; I will turn my back and stretch my hand.
When I see the pain, I feel it myself.
I said Lord, Lord, I will not be able to pass this hospital.
Where are we going?
We now approached the chief medical director there.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
He said, "many of these people don't have machines for dialysis and they are so many". I said, "OK".
I said, "look, I am going back. I am not going to be able to go far. Let me go back, I am going to see mayor".
They said, "let us move forward", I said, "no, no I am going to see mayor".
When I got to mayor, they asked, "have you finished moving around?" I said, "no, no I can't move around".
I saw people on sick beds, they said there are no machines for dialysis...
What can we do to support? These people should not die just like that.
The mayor now gives a call to the chief medical director.
"What are the challenges about dialysis machines?"
They said they need almost 20 to 30 dialysis machines.
I said, "right now I am going to provide them."
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We have provided the machines for them as I am talking now, they are with them.
We provided the machines, dialysis machines. We provided all for them.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
And the woman mayor said, [surprise sound]
Yes!
Don't call me by my name Prophet,
call me LOVE.
My name is LOVE.
LET LOVE LEAD
You are the one who calls me prophet, pastor, bishop whatever name you call me
That is the name you gave me. But the name God gave me from heaven is LOVE.
Are you with me?
You call me bishop, prophet, general overseer of the Synagogue whatever name,
I will answer you because I don't want to hurt you
You say, "Papa",...huuhuu
How can you see [Running Standing Still]
Can you Papa at home do like this? [Running Standing Still]
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When you see me like this and call me Papa God will forgive you.
You cannot be Papa twice only once. Young once, old once, brother once, sister once, once you are sister;
as time goes on they will not call you sister again.
Wait for the when I will be Papa.
LET LOVE LEAD
Let someone say let love lead.
We are all one.
Whatever you can do to change the world, whatever; change the world.
Don't begin to hide under Jesus Christ.
Don't hide under Christianity.
Don't hide under the name bishop, the name prophet.
Change and help!
Save souls.
I know many of us will, "Ha, we have many hospitals in Nigeria,
that are in need of dialysis machines."
But what about our name that has been spoiled all over the world? How do we repair this name?
That name Nigeria where I travel all over,
they look at Nigeria differently, they say, "no, no, no this one is from Nigeria? No.
What you are saying about Nigeria is quite different".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You that can do the one at home, continue doing it. We that can do the one outside,
the name that has been spoiled outside, let us go and repair that name.
The belief is that Africans are only to ask anywhere we enter: give me, give me, give me...
That is the impression of people outside the world.
No matter how rich an African man...
It is always: give me, give me, give me...
No we should change this impression.
We too can give.
We can give out of the little we have. Let's give, let's begin to give.
You say you are poor. Who told you are poor?
Your parents told you you are poor. But God does not say that you are poor.
Give!
Let them know that, no; the time of "give us, give us is over."
It is also the time we can give them and they too give us.
Give us, give us...Let us give, let us exchange.
The western world over the world are human beings like us.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
It is not that I have so much. But I just feel that out of the little I have I can give.
To change some impression we found
when we were little. But for the generation of yesterday and the generation of today,
the impression we create outside the world is very very bad.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We are not doing it to show off, no. It is a way of letting love lead.
LET LOVE LEAD.
Like I have said. A lot of things are going on all over the world, all over the world.
In Africa, there are problems. We are the ones destroying our continent.
We use our mouth to destroy our continent.
We don't appreciate our people.
I mean we don't appreciate our people.
After meeting the mayor I was taken to the parliament.
While sitting, I looked at myself and I remembered my Africa and I said, Oh! I nearly cried and I said, Africa!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I was talking about universities last time and African universities all over.
Can you believe that I am invited to an American university?
One of the biggest university to come and give a lecture.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I am invited in Alabama and in many other states to come and give lectures.
The students say, "yes we want this man to come and speak to us".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
These are the big universities and I am still in between asking God
Should I go or not go?
I know if I just visit one, all over the world I will be receiving invitations to give lectures at universities.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I pray the Lord will give me an opportunity to visit some of these universities.
I have my area of specialization I am going to talk about. I am not a professor.
But I will talk about an area where they would appreciate God better.
Education is not success, it is to help us succeed.
It is not that success, but it helps us succeed.
That is why you can be a criminal or anything and still graduate first class.
You can be one of the cult members in the school,
You can be a criminal or a tug, this is why we find it difficult to understand our children.
We love them because they are very brilliant, but we don't know that some of them are criminals.
They are very brilliant but at the same time they are criminals.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Why should this be?
If you are very brilliant, you should not be a criminal.
Why should you be a criminal and the best student in the school?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
A tug and the best student in the school, first class.
Why these two things should go together?
This is where children of God get confused.
You say, I read, read, I read, look at me, third class.
And this guy I know him to be very wayward in the school.
He is a member of a cult and is first class.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So, this is why children of God get confused.
You say, I read, I read all the time, I read my book all the time, I pray, I fast,
I meet my pastor for prayer and other but at the end I came third class.
But I know this student very wayward, he never believes God. He always goes to parties, night clubs;
and I don't know when he or she reads but now first class.
This is an area where students need someone to come and talk to them.
Why things should happen like that so that they will not get confused that God is unfaithful.
Students need to understand this...
If you have prayed and you have been walking in the Lord, in the love;
and you have been doing the right thing and you know that you are a believer.
And at the end of the day you came third class, give thank to God;
because your third class will give you a better future than first class.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
That is why today when you look at the record of heroes, generals; people that are there (up) today
90% of them came third class.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Even the lowest third class.
Even failure.
But today they are the heroes.
Whereas 80% of people on the street that will say I am a graduate are first class.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
80% that are on the street looking for jobs or
doing what they have not been prayed to do, what they are not planning or they do not like to do;
80% of them are first class.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
It is not about what you come out with. It is the force behind what you come out with.
I can have $5 and you have $10,000
And my $5 will be more valuable than your $10,000.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I repeat again.
I may have $10,000 and you have $1,000,000. My $10,000 will be more valuable than your $1,000,000.
It depends on how we came up with the money: the processing.
It is process that works.
What works? [process]
I can't hear you [process]
Look at marriages today.
Many marriages that the whole world celebrate with gifts of billions of dollars,
90% of such marriages are broken today.
Whereas some marriages nobody knew about are the ones still there as husband and wife.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Process, let someone say process [process]. If your process to acquire first class is not Godly,
but you are very brilliant and you have not lived a Godly life;
and someone whose process is Godly
and later came out third class, lowest, or even failure or pass.
He will achieve what we call greatness in the future than you that have the first class.
It is a matter of time.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You people are out there you have many histories.
Look at all this Facebook we are talking about. The founder of Facebook.
You go and read about him that young man. He abandoned university.
So, the question is about process.
The process of your marriage.
The process of being a pastor.
The process of being a prophet.
The process of being president of a country.
The process of being a senator of a country.
The process of being head of a department.
That process will continue to work for you, work against you, work for you.
How do you become the Managing Director of the company?
You are a Managing Director. You know you run to witch doctors
to make sure that the former Managing Director is dismissed.
The result does not matter; process matters.
Your results may be bad but your process is good. It is a matter of time; fold your hand.
[Clapping]
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You may be dismissed unlovely and someone is asked to take your position.
It is a matter of time; fold your hand.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So, all this is life.
This is why you see people like me here today.
It is because of process that I am still alive.
It is not because of results. It is not because of what is happening, miracles, this or that...
That is not the reason why I am still alive and got stronger.
It is because of process. I quietly follow the process of the Lord.
I know the Lord will be there for me. [Amen, Clapping]
The SCOAN Sunday Service
That is process.
Process!
If you dupe your fellow brother to get a billion dollars and become a millionaire; it is not yet over.
Process, let someone say process. It is not yet over.
It is not yet over; it is a matter of time. You, you will still crumble from there.
And you will be on the street begging.
Let someone say process.
So that is why for many of you, any time there is trouble,
somebody duped you, somebody tried to do something against you, you are so bitter. Don't be bitter.
Keep holding on to God. No one can cheat you and go.
It is a matter of time.
If somebody takes something that belongs to you, it takes it away and is using it; it is a matter of time.
Process.
So the problem many of you are facing today is as a result of the wrong process
because you want to follow shortcuts.
It is a normal thing that 1 + 1 + 1 is equal to 3.
But you want to say 1 + 2.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If I am talking to you (you understand) that the normal process to get 3 is 1 + 1 + 1 is equal to what? [3]
But in your own case because you are impatient; it is 1 + 2.
That 2 you don't want to simplify it or break it at all; you want to have 3 immediately.
If it was possible you would say 3 is equal to 3.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
It is not too late; you can start afresh because God loves you so much.
If you have taken a wrong process; start afresh.
If it is a wrong process you have followed and you are getting and enjoying it [hummm...]
A time is coming.
The SCOAN Sunday service
So please work as if everything depends on you and pray as if everything depends on God.
Say it again!
Again!
[Work as if everything depends on you and pray as if everything depends on God.]
I can't hear you!
Work as if everything depends on you. That is when you are working hard and hard; put all your effort.
While you are praying to God...
We don't know how to pray.
The Holy Spirit helps us in our weakness.
Work as if everything depends on you and pray as if everything...
Tell your children at home: Read as if everything depends on you pray as if everything depends on God.
Tell it to your children. So please.
Thank you
God bless you!
The SCOAN Sunday service